<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>async and await</title>
      <link>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/dotnet/asyncawait/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 08:32:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/dotnet/asyncawait/</guid>
      <description>tldr async and await are keywords in C# to let code continue executing while waiting on a long operation (like downloading a file) to complete.
Typically, I write synchronous code because it is easier to debug, after it works, then I&amp;rsquo;ll use async/await.
To make async methods synchronous (i.e. block further code execution until method finishes), add .Result to the end of the method call. E.g. client.DownloadFileAsync().Result
Quick code snippet This is how you create a batch of web requests to run in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignoring Types</title>
      <link>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/dotnet/dynamictypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 08:32:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/dotnet/dynamictypes/</guid>
      <description>Strongly typed vs dynamically typed Strongly typed means that the compiler will complain if a method does not exist in the class specified during variable declaration. C# is strongly typed, but if you are used to dynamically typed languages (like Python), you can do that too.
//strongly typed Animal duck = Factory.MakeDuck(); duck.quack(); //compile error because quack() is not defined in Animal even though you know the underlying object is a duck  Dynamically typed means that the compiler will not care whether the method exists or not (it will be done at runtime)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection</title>
      <link>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/dotnet/reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 08:32:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/dotnet/reflection/</guid>
      <description>If you have scripting language that allows you to call C# (e.g. Powershell), or if you want to call undocumented private methods, then you need to learn how to use Reflection.
What is &amp;ldquo;reflection&amp;rdquo;? It&amp;rsquo;s a way of programatically examining and calling code from an assembly (.dll/.exe) at runtime.
The examples here are in C#, but the concepts apply when you are using scripting languages that use .NET.
Load C# Objects How would you use classes from a different dll without importing it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Modules</title>
      <link>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/powershell/modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 08:32:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/powershell/modules/</guid>
      <description>There are Script modules (.psm1 files) and Binary modules (aka cmdlets)
Script Module A script module is essentially any valid PowerShell script saved in a .psm1 extension.
function Show-Calendar { } Export-ModuleMember -Function Show-Calendar  The paths where you can install your module are located in the $env:PSModulePath global variable. Be sure to create a folder for your module to exist in, even if it is only a single .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging with no source</title>
      <link>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/dotnet/decompiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 08:32:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/dotnet/decompiler/</guid>
      <description>No Source? No Problem. Well-known decompilers are .NET Reflector, ILSpy. These will restore the source code from .NET dll or exe files (aka assemblies). You can even save the decompiled source as a csproj.
One step further A newer tool called &amp;ldquo;dnSpy&amp;rdquo; https://github.com/0xd4d/dnSpy lets you debug and edit .NET assemblies! (you can attach to a running process as well as launch)
To debug webapps running in IISExpress, you need to view the debug output from Visual Studio and find your dll in that list (because IISexpress copies the dlls to temp locations).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove creds from code</title>
      <link>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/azure/keyvault/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 20:31:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://efficienthacks.github.io/coderbook/azure/keyvault/</guid>
      <description>The code Here&amp;rsquo;s how to do it quickly in a Console application (works the same way when you do it for a web application - sample web app project available in &amp;lsquo;Further Reading&amp;rsquo; section):
using Microsoft.Azure.KeyVault; using Microsoft.Azure.Services.AppAuthentication; static void Main(string[] args) { string secretstr,error ; var azureServiceTokenProvider = new AzureServiceTokenProvider(&amp;quot;RunAs=Developer; DeveloperTool=AzureCli&amp;quot;); //this is an optional parameter to use the same creds as &amp;quot;az login&amp;quot; in Azure CLI (a command line tool that you have to install separately), remove this when you deploy it in Azure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>